HDFC Ergo Optima Secure or ICICI LBAD
Elevate Health Insurance Plan When you
look at both these plans, they will
appear almost the same.  Both are
plans of good brands.  Apart from this,
very good features have been provided in both.
But when it comes to
how much money we may have to pay from our pocket under these plans at the time of any claim
or
which plan is going to be more affordable in the next 5 years
how have these companies performed in terms of claims in the past.
If we
go deeper into these details,
you may notice a lot of difference between these two plans.  And the
right time to find out this difference is not when
we get admitted to the hospital for some treatment
and file a claim.
We cannot change anything at that time.
Therefore, in today's video,
apart from the basic differences between these two plans, I am
also going to show you some such details and data
which no insurance agent,
broker or insurance company will tell you.   First of all,
we will understand what is the USP of both these plans
?  You will understand the difference in coverage and benefits
well.  Then we will
learn about add ons and
also compare pricing.  Then finally I am going to show you
some very important data on complaints and claims.  This will give
you a
better understanding of how these companies
are when it comes to claims.  Because
my only purpose of making this video is
that you
take your decision with maximum information so that
you do not face any problem at the time of claims.
If you have come to this channel for the first time or
you have not subscribed to the channel yet, then
please subscribe
so that you keep getting similar important videos
in the future also.  Let's start
the video.  First of all friends, let us talk about the
USP of HDFCO Optima Secure Plan.
So there are total four US pieces in it.   The first one
is the secure benefit.  That is why the
name of the plan is Optima Secure.  In which,
whatever amount you
buy as basic sum insured, you can claim double sum insured from the very first day.
Suppose
you can get coverage of ₹20 lakh for ₹1 lakh from the very first day.
Apart from this, you get Plus benefit
inside Optima Secure plan.
Within which, irrespective of claim, 50%
cumulative bonus can increase up to a maximum of 100%.
That is, the basic sum assured of ₹1 lakh
becomes ₹1 lakh after two renewals.
Other than that, Protect Benefit
is also an inbuilt feature which covers
non-medical items like cotton gloves which can be up
to 10 to 15% of the total claim amount.
You will also get coverage for this
under the Optima Secure plan.  And the fourth
benefit is the restoration benefit
in which your basic sum insured or secure
benefit or other benefits are lost.
So,
you can also use the restoration benefit equal to the basic sum insured once a year
for any treatment.  You can also choose it unlimited times through add ons.
Apart from this,
HDFCGO has recently launched three new add-ons,
which include Parenthood, which is a
replacement for maternity, and Limitless, under which
you can stretch a single claim up to an unlimited amount.
And if your sum
insured is high then there can be two such claims.
And the third add-on is ABCD
Chronic Care Rider in which you can provide coverage for Asthma,
BP, Diabetes or Cholesterol from the 31st
day.  If a
policy holder already has these problems then he will
not have to wait.  2 years 3 years You
can avail coverage from 31st day with
Chronic Care Rider Additional premium will have to be
paid by you.  This was about the
USP of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure Plan.  You might
know them well because
you have heard about them in many videos.  It has been a
long time since the plan was launched.
Now let's talk about the
USP of ICICI LBRD Elevate Plan.  So the
insurance company has kept the theme here as
Infinite.  Infinite means unlimited.   There are a
total of four such benefits in which the
company has not kept any limits.  The first one
is Unlimited Sum Insured.  You must have noticed that
within the plan you choose sum insured as 5 lakh, 10
lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh.  You
can also avail unlimited sum insured under the Elevate plan.  The second benefit
is infinite reset.  This
is a restoration benefit in which your
amount will be restored unlimited times.  As you will
use this money for any treatment.  The
third USP is Power Booster which is
its unlimited loyalty bonus.  The policy will
provide you with an additional sum insured equal to your basic sum insured on renewal every year till unlimited times for a policy of ₹1 lakh.  Whether
the claim is made or not,
this ₹10 lakh will keep increasing every year with the same
premium.  The fourth USP is the Infinite
Care add-on.  Under this, you can stretch
any one claim up
to an unlimited amount during the entire policy life time.
Suppose you have a policy of ₹1 lakh but
a big claim comes and you have
taken this add-on Infinite Care Add-on,
then you can remove the sum insured limit from that claim.
You will be
able to get treatment expenses up to unlimited amount from the company.
Apart from this, you can also add maternity in ICC LBA Delivered Plan
through add-on.  The
company has also offered jump start as an add-on.
Under which you can cover conditions like asthma, BP, diabetes and
hypertension for 31 days.
Coverage of non-medical items i.e. consumables
is included in the Elevate plan.  But you have to take it as an add on.
This is not inbuilt in the standard plan.
As was the case
with the Optima Secure plan.  We will discuss which lists are covered under these
in the coverage and benefits section.  If we
look at the USPs of both the plans, they
appear quite strong.  But until we
know the detailed coverage and benefits and all the add-ons and
review the pricing, it
is difficult to say anything.  So let us first
understand the eligibility conditions and their differences, that when you go to buy this plan,
what is the difference in the terms and conditions there.  Talking about the entry
age, the
minimum entry age for HDFC Ergo Optima Secure plan is 18 years
for any adult and there is no maximum entry
age limit.  If we talk about
dependent children, that is, those children who are currently
non-earning and are unmarried and are in
a family floater plan with their parents.
Those children can remain as age dependent children with
their parents in Optima Secure plan for a maximum period of 25 years.
Whereas, under the ICICI LBA Elevate plan, the
minimum entry age for adults is 18 years and the
maximum age is 125 years.  That means technically there
is no age limit.  If we talk about
dependent children, there
is a slight gap here.  Dependent children can
stay with their parents under this plan for up to 30 years.
Now let's talk about the sum insured
options.  So,
under the Optima Secure plan, you get flexible options of minimum ₹5 lakh and maximum ₹2 crore.
Whereas in ICICI LB Elevate plan, the
minimum sum assured is ₹5 lakh and
you can choose a fixed sum assured of maximum ₹3 crore.
Apart from this, the
option of unlimited sum insured is also available.
You can choose any plan type from both the companies.  You
can also opt for a family floater plan that
covers the entire family under a common sum insured, which is
also affordable.  Apart from this, you
can also take individual sum insured.   This
means that you will get separate money for coverage of each member.
These options are available in both the plans.  Now let's talk about
what is the maximum family size that can be covered under a family floater plan?  If so,
coverage can be given to four adults and six dependent children under HDFC and Optima Secure plans.  Whereas under ICICI LB
Elevate Plan, you can take two adults and three
dependent children in the family float
plan.  In both these
plans, you
get the option to renew the life long policy.  That means there is
no maximum time when this
plan will end.
You can renew this policy for life long.  Now
friends, let's talk about policy tenure.
That is, how many term policies can you buy at one time
?  This often gives you extra
discounts and saves you from long-term
inflationary revisions,
which often increase premiums due to inflation.
You can buy a maximum of 3 years policy at a time under Optima Secure Plan.
Whereas, under ICICI LBA Elevate Plan, a
plan can be taken for a maximum of 5 years
and the longer the period, the
more discount you get on paying the premium all at once.
Now that we are talking about premium, it
is very important to discuss the age band
as there is a huge difference here.   There
is no age banded premium under HDFC Argo Optima Secure plan.  That means,
as your age increases,
your premium will definitely increase every year on renewal.
But if we talk about ICCI
LBD Elevate Plan, then there you
get age banded premium.  This means
your premium will remain the same within a fixed age band of 5 years.
Suppose you have purchased the plan
at the age of 25, then
your premium will remain the same from 26 to 30 years.  It will be
revised again in 31.  There are five-year age
bands where your premium will be
revised once.  And this age that I am telling you will be
considered for the senior member in the family floater plan.  Now after comparing the eligibility conditions of both these plans, it
seems to me that
ICICI LBD Elevate Plan may prove to be cost-wise
effective in the long term.  There are two-three reasons for this.  The
first reason is that the dependent
child can stay for 5 more years in ICICI LBA
Elevate Plan.  Because you know that
dependent child gets some discount
on premium due to which your
premium gets reduced.  Apart from this,
you can also take a long term policy for 5 years instead of 3
in the Elevate plan.  And the
most important premium is edge banded.
That means there will be no one with revision age in it for 5 years.
However,
companies can make inflationary revisions at any time.
But considering these conditions, I
think the Elevate plan may prove to be cost effective in the long term.
In the rest of the pricing section, we will see
what exactly premium you get for these plans along with some selected add-ons.
You will know the correct difference from there also.
Now friends, let's talk about some such
differences.  There are differences
in the coverage of these two plans.  The first
difference is in the room rent limit.
Under HDFC Optima Secure plan, you
get the actual room rent expenses covered on Edge.
Whereas, the capping in the ICIC LBD Elevate plan
is for single private AC room.
This capping is within the standard plan.
But you can also modify it.
For which extra premium will have to be taken.
If you upgrade but downgrade, the
premium may be slightly lower.
What does this difference mean?  See,
when we get admitted to the hospital for treatment,
we are given a particular category of
room.  The
S written on the Optima Secure plan means
that the insurance company will provide you coverage for whatever category of room the hospital
provides you.
Whereas under the Elevate plan, you
cannot take a room above the single private AC room.  If you buy the Standard plan.
But which room will the hospital, especially network
hospitals, give you?  This is decided in
advance with the insurance company regarding their
package rates
and conditions.  So this
kind of capping in network hospitals does not cause much trouble.
But still, if you
want the freedom that this limit should
not have any impact on your claim amount in future.  If no
money is deducted then not having actuals or any
temporary limit on edge can be very beneficial for you.
Apart from this, coverage of day care
treatment is included in both the plans.  There
is a slight difference in pre and post hospitalization expenses.  HDFC
Aurama Secure plan offers only 60 days
coverage for pre-hospitalization
expenses.  Any expenses incurred before you take any treatment
related to the same will be covered for 2 months
before you get admitted.  Whereas
in the ICC Lombard Elevate Plan, this number of
days is 90 days.  Post hospitalization
is same in both, 180 days.  So here comes the difference of 30 days,
which means
you get more coverage in the ICC Lobbered Elevate plan.
Apart from this, under both the plans,
domiciliary treatment i.e. treatment at home, if
due to some compulsion there
are no beds in the hospitals or the
condition of the patient is very bad, then
this coverage will be available under both the plans.  Along with this,
Ayush treatment
is also available in both the plans.  AYUSH means
alternative treatments such as Ayurveda,
Yoga, Naturopathy, Unani and Homeopathy.
Inpatient treatment, i.e., treatment requiring
admission to a certified AYUSH
facility or day care center, can be
covered under both plans.  Along with
this,
you also get coverage for organ transplant under both these plans.
If we talk about road ambulance,
then
you will also get it under standard coverage in both the plans.  And
if we talk about air ambulance, you get inbuilt
coverage of up to ₹5 lakh in the Optima Secure plan.
Under the Elevate plan, you will have to take an add-on for air
ambulance.  Apart from this, there are some wellness
benefits also.  Like annual health
checkup.
You will get this feature inbuilt in Optima Secure plan.  At the same time,
you will have to take this add-on within the ICICI LBR plan.
Similarly, e-opinion i.e.
tele-consultation is also
available inbuilt in the Optima Secure plan.
You will have to take it as an add-on under the ICICD Elevate plan.
Apart from this, there is
also a daily cash back benefit which
you get in the Optima Secure plan.  In which
you will get ₹800 per day.  If you
use shared accommodation during treatment, i.e.,
stay in a room with other patients,
then you can be given a benefit of ₹800 per day up to a maximum of ₹4800.
ICC LB
Elevate Plan does not offer such a benefit.
But the ICC LBD Elevate plan has many
small features that can
add coverage to your policy.
But the company has given them the option to
choose through add-ons, which we will
understand in the next section i.e. the add-ons section.   The
first rider I am going to tell you about from HDFC and OPTima Secure is
Limitless.
Under the Limitless Rider, if your sum insured
is between ₹1 lakh and ₹50 lakh, then
you can
remove the sum insured limit from any claim once during the entire policy life.
If the sum insured is more than this,
then you can take two such claims in the entire policy life time in
which there will be
no limit on the sum insured.  A similar add-
on is available in the Elevate plan called Infinite Care,
which allows you to make
a claim up to an unlimited amount during the lifetime of the policy.  The
second rider
in the Optima Secure plan is Parenthood,
under which you can avail maternity coverage.  That
means two deliveries, normal and C-section, can be
covered.  Apart from this,
you can also get coverage for two cycles of procedures like IVF.
But there is a small drawback in this rider
that the coverage of the new born baby is
not included in the paternity rider.  Against this, the
maternity rider that comes under the ICIC LBAD Elevate
plan also allows
you to get coverage for normal and C-section delivery.
You will get a claim of 10% of the total sum insured and a maximum of ₹1 lakh for this.
But it also includes coverage for new born babies.  The
limit of which is two times your maternity sum
insured.  That means, if the
coverage of ₹1 lakh is for maternity, then ₹1 lakh can be
used for the treatment of a newborn baby, i.e. a child whose age is less than 90 days.  The
third rider
in Optima Secure is ABC D Chronic Care
Rider, in which I told you that
coverage of Asthma, BP, Diabetes, Cholesterol can be taken from 31 days.   A
similar add-on is also available within the Elevate plan,
called Jump Start.  Within that
also, coverage can be taken from 31 days.  Now these
add ons do provide you coverage
but whenever you buy a policy, you should
definitely ask this question that are these types of add
ons which are reducing the waiting period.  For
how many years will you have to pay its premium
?  Because companies may have different
calculations for each plan.
In some plans, this type of premium is charged for three years, in some for five years, in some for only
one year
so that you can identify the actual cost of this add-on.
And the second advice I
would like to give about ABCD Rider is that if
this condition has been recently diagnosed.   If
someone has BP or is pre-diabetic then there is
no need to take these.
Because he has two-three years time.  This is a
very mild condition.  They are manageable in the beginning.
Those who have been living
with these conditions for many years and feel
that a major claim may come within a year
or they are suffering a lot, then
they should take such riders in
which coverage is available after 31 days.   The
next add-on is critical illness.   The
Optima Secure plan offers a sum insured ranging from
₹1 lakh to ₹2 crore upon diagnosis of any of the 51 critical illnesses listed.
Whereas,
this add-on is available in the ICICI Labord Elevate plan
but the list of critical illnesses is quite small.
Only 20 conditions are covered
and the maximum sum insured is ₹50 lakh.
Apart from this,
you get the add-on of unlimited restoration in Optima Secure,
which should be taken because this
single time restoration feature
is available in the standard plan.  The reset benefit in the Elevate plan
is already unlimited, so there is
no need for any add-on.  Now friends, comes the
most powerful add-on of ICICI Elevate plan
which is Power Booster.  I had told you
that the amount equal to your sum insured will keep
increasing by 100% on every renewal, that too
irrespective of claims.  Even if you are
making a claim but the money is not used, the
100% sum insured will continue to increase
and this will happen unlimited times.  I don't know
how viable such features are in the future.
But currently
you do not get any such feature in Optima Secure plan.
You will get plus benefits in that.
₹20 lakh sum insured can be yours with ₹1 lakh at 50% on the first renewal and 50% on the next renewal.
But in the Elevate plan,
it will keep increasing every year equal to the sum insured.
Apart from this,
you can also get coverage for personal accident under both the plans.  In
which, whatever sum insured is chosen,
if any insured person dies
accidentally, then the
company will pay the lump sum benefit of the chosen amount to that family
or nominee.  Apart from this, you can also get
some OPD coverage under both these plans.
Optima Secure has an
add-on called Optima Well Being and
ICICI LBR Elevate offers Be Fit Rider,
which offers
limited OPD coverage.
Apart from this, there is also an inflation protection add-on in the ICICI LBR Elevate plan, in
which the sum insured will keep increasing
every year according to the inflation rate as per the Consumer Price Index with the
same
premium.  Optima Secure plan does
not have such a feature.  Because there are many such add-
ons which have been launched in the latest plans and
these features are provided in them.  HDFC Ago has
introduced only three new add-ons.  About which the
company felt that these add-ons were a
must.  That's why the Parenthood Limitless and
ABCD Chronic Care Rider company has just
launched.  Now friends, before I
take you to the pricing section, let us quickly
understand the waiting period of both these plans.   The
initial waiting period is 30 days.  This means that if
you purchase both the plans, then within the first 30
days, no
claim other than accidental treatments will be available under these plans.  The
second waiting period is
specific diseases which are listed medical condition
surgeries will be covered after 24 months.
However, this waiting period can
also be reduced within the Elevate plan.  Apart from this
comes the PED waiting
period.  Any medical condition that
you currently have at the time of purchasing the policy and that you declare at the
time of taking the policy, then the company will
cover it after 36 months i.e. 3 years.
However, this can also be reduced under the Elevate plan
by paying
extra premium.  If we talk about the
waiting period for critical illness, then there is a
waiting period of 90 days in the Elevate plan.
If any serious illness is diagnosed within the first three months, the
company will not cover it.  No
such waiting period is mentioned in the Optima Secure plan.
Maternity has a
standard waiting period.
24 months in both the plans.  If you
buy the policy today,
this plan will cover any delivery expenses after 24 months.
Friends, to compare pricing, I have come
to the Policyba platform because it becomes very easy to compare the pricing of multiple plans
at one place.
First, let's
look at the pricing of the Optima Secure plan.  I have taken family size
for both the plans.  Two adults and one
child.  The age of the adults is 37 and 33
years and the child is 10 years old.  His address is
New Delhi.  Optimal Secure
Plan offers coverage of ₹1 lakh as an
additional secure benefit of ₹1 lakh from
day one.  One add-on I have
chosen here is Unlimited Restoration.
Apart from this, I do not feel any add-on is necessary for this age group and
this family.
However,
I would definitely like to show you the price of parenthood.
Now see two deliveries will be covered.  There
is a waiting period of 2 years and
for a coverage of ₹1 lakh, you will have to pay an additional ₹25,270
and let us assume that
you will buy the policy today and
keep the policy for one year.  After the first year, renewal for the second year will
come.  Then you will keep the policy for the second year
, only when the third year renewal comes, you will
get maternity coverage.  Till then you will end up
paying almost ₹76,000 and
get coverage of ₹1 lakh maternity benefits.  So the
cost to benefit ratio doesn't seem to be anything special to me.
But I will
also compare the pricing with the Elevate plan.
So you can see that ₹25,270 has been
added for maternity.  The total
premium comes to ₹26,421 for ₹1 lakh basic sum assured.
Now friends, we will see the price of ICICI LBA Elevate
Plan.  We will look at the Basic Sum Insured in
two ways here because there is a
secure benefit there.  ₹20 lakh coverage is
from day one.  So, firstly we will take coverage of ₹1 lakh
and along with it we will take power booster add on in
which ₹1 lakh will keep increasing every year.
After this I will show you
how much premium is coming for ₹20 lakh.  If you
take a sum insured of ₹20 lakh from the very first day, then
how much premium will it cost?  So the
basic sum insured is ₹1 lakh.
We will have to take some add-ons in this because they are
not part of the standard plan.  As
I said about power booster, let's add it.
Apart from this, there is a claim protector which will
provide you coverage for non-medical items.
So I have added this here also.
Optima Secure plan has Plus
benefits.  And what is special about both?
Only List One of Annexure One
is covered in both.  That means the remaining three lists are
not covered.  If there is ever a deduction, there are
chances that almost the same amount will be deducted from both the plans.  That are related to
non-medical items consumable items because
only List One is covered under it.  If you
modify the room rent for any room, it may
cost ₹961.  If there is a single private AC
room then we add it.  Let's take you to Annie's room.
Annual health checkup
is inbuilt in it, so we will add it also.   Apart from this,
look at the maternity package.  Now let's
look at the maternity pricing here.
Maternity pricing is ₹1 lakh
for delivery and newborn pay of ₹1 lakh is also
covered.
This is very expensive at ₹45,000.  If we add this then the
premium goes up to almost Rs 70,000.
So I don't think maternity
is affordable under either plan.  The
premium is also higher because
it also covers newborn babies.
But at least Optima Secure
plan's maternity is more affordable than this.  But
I think there is
no coverage for newborn babies in it.  Whereas coverage of newborn baby must be there.
Because the
most vulnerable and sensitive are both the mother and the new
born baby.  So coverage of both is a
must in any maternity plan.
So right now I do
n't find the price of Rs 45,000 affordable here
and hence I am not adding it
but I have shown you how much
premium will be there.  So here I have
added some essential add ons which I felt were necessary to make it at
par with Optima Secure plan.
So the total premium comes to
₹23,464.
HDFCO's premium came to ₹26,400.   That
means there is a difference of only ₹3000.  But
in the Elevate plan, the sum insured was
₹1 lakh.  Now let me show you another option to
review the pricing.
We will choose the basic sum assured of ₹20
lakh.  Because Optima Secure
also provides coverage of ₹20 lakh from the first day.
And from here I remove the rider of the power booster.
Now here the premium increases to
₹27,562
which is approximately ₹1000 more expensive than HDFC's ₹2,400.  That
means
if you take a basic sum insured of ₹20 lakhs,
then ICICI LBARD is going to be a
little more expensive
than HDFCO.  But if you want the sum
insured to be only ₹1 lakh and the plan
remains affordable, then you can add on the Power Booster from
here.  That will cost you less.
But keep in mind that there is a
huge difference between features like cumulative bonus and power booster and the basic sum insured.
If you port or
migrate the plan, the company will consider your
basic sum insured as the minimum sum
insured.  The
company may not consider such features like bonuses.
So friends, after comparing this pricing,
I understand one thing
that in the beginning the pricing is almost equal.
When we equate the features and
weigh both the plans on the same scale, there is
not much difference in pricing.
But the thing to think about is
that this premium may
increase significantly in the coming years.  There could be two or three factors for this.
Like the premium one with Edge.   The
senior member of the ICC LBA Elevate Plan is
37 years old.  So their premium will
not increase for the next 4 years.  This will remain premium.
But within HDFC Ergo, this
premium will keep increasing slightly every year.
And apart from this, if there is
any revision due to inflation, then
it is unpredictable.
We cannot say anything about that right now.  But just
looking at the price will not be enough.  Now let
me show you the claims
performance of both these companies, how
these companies have performed in terms of claim settlement in the last few years
so that you can better
relate these two things as to which
company is charging how much premium for which type of claim performance.
Now friends, I have brought you to the
claims dashboard.  This claims
data is purely health insurance
claims.  The data for the last three years has been
taken from the public disclosure documents of insurance companies.
Starting from financial year 2020,
how many claims has the company settled in these three years 23, 23 and 24
?  By taking the average of these three
years, I have calculated some metrics and
some ratios for you here.  The
first ratio is the claim
settlement ratio.  So the
average claim settlement ratio of ICICI LBARD between 2022 and 2025
is 86.39%
which is much lower than HDFC.  HDFC
Hgo has settled 96 out of every 100 claims.
This ratio shows us the
efficiency of the company in claim settlement.
How many claims is she able to settle?  The
second ratio is the claims paid
ratio.  This was the number of claims
settled.  The claims paid ratio will
show us how much money the company has paid out.
If the policy holder claims ₹100
from the insurance company, ICICI LBARD has
paid ₹68 out of that.  This is the average of the last 3 years.
HDFC Ago has paid ₹82 out
of ₹100.  So
HDFC RGO data is better in both claim settlement ratio and claims paid ratio.
This means that
ICICI LBARD has refused to give a lot of money to the policy holders.
Many claims have been
rejected.  So this means that the policy
holders must have complained.  So
after this I will show you the data of complaints also.
What are the complaints of the Insurance Observer
and what are the resolutions made in it.   The
next data comes is the incurred claim ratio.
How much money was taken from the policy holders throughout the year
and how many claims were given in return.
ICICI LBRD collected ₹100 in premium and paid
health claims worth ₹84 between 2022 and 25.  HDFCO
gave an estimated ₹86.  I gave approximately ₹87.
Both these incurred claim ratios are good for the policy holders.  But
here too, HDFC Ergo has a higher incurred claim
ratio.  Now friends, let's talk about
solvency margin.  That means the
insurance company should always have one
and a half times the amount of liability of the sum insured through the policies.
Such are the guidelines of IRDA.
ICIC LBRD has 2.62
times i.e. if it has a liability of ₹100, it has
₹262 in return.  That means he
is in a very comfortable position financially.
HDFC Ago also has 1.89 i.e. almost two
times money which is more than one and a half times the benchmark.
But ICICI LBRD
is in a better financial position in the past three
years.  Now friends, let's talk about the number of
complaints, 10,000 claims.
What is the average number of complaints in both the companies in the last 3 years?  For every 10,000
health insurance claims filed,
11 complaints come to ICICI Laboratories
and these are the complaints that we handle
in the Grievances Department.  We
complained directly to the company.  These are those
complaints.  Similarly, only
approximately 11 complaints were registered within HDFC Ago, which is the
average of the last three years.  So here
both the companies seem equal to me.
If I look at the first two ratios,
Claim Settlement Ratio and Claims Paid
Ratio, then obviously I see HDFCGO Optima
Secure performing better
based on last three years
claims data.  And the amount paid by ICC LBD is
comparatively very less.   There
is a huge gap here.  Now friends,
I have brought you to the complaints data.
This is the complaints data from the Insurance
Ombudsman's Annual Report, which is the
latest available annual
report for the year 2024-25.  Here, the
total complaints filed by HDFC Bank
in Insurance Ombudsman
were 1542, out of which
1117 have been disposed of.  425
are pending.  ICICI LBD
received 974 complaints in this financial year, out
of which 723 have been disposed of.  That means the number of complaints with HDFC
Ergo Insurance Brokersman is
more than that of ICICI Laboratories in this financial year.  Secondly,
I want to show you the bar graph of the data
that how many of these complaints
went in favor of the policy holder and how many
complaints went in favor of the insurance company.
So first of all, if we look at HDFC Ergo, the
ratio of total complaints has been almost 50-50%.  That means, if 100
complaints were registered, in half of them the
customer got relief and in half the complaints
either went in favor of the company or the customer
withdrew the complaint.  That means there may have been any decision that did
not go in favor of the customer.
He is in the remaining 50%.  If we
look at the data of ICICI LBD, there
is a huge gap here and what is that gap?  In
64% of the 100 complaints, the policy
holder did not get any relief
even from the Insurance Ombudsman.  This means that these complaints have either been
rolled in favor of the insurance company
or the company has already settled them.  The
complaint has been withdrawn.  But out
of the total complaints, only 35%
complaints have been rolled in favor of the policy holder.  The
decision has been given in his favour.
If you look at both these data.  Which one
?  One is the claims paid ratio in which the
claims paid ratio was 6768%, that is, the
company is paying only ₹68 out of 100.  After that
people might be complaining and the complaints are
also being rolled in the company's favor.
This means that even after
complaining to the Insurance Ombudsman, the
decision is going in favor of the company.
So the initial
rejection from the company was also valid.  That was also right.
This means that the insurance company takes the
implementation of its policy contract and policy wordings very seriously.  There
is no scope for any mistake.   There will be no
problem in genuine claim.
But ICICI Labord is not going to leave
any loophole or deficiency as per the policy contract.
Whether we
complain to the insurance man or to the
grievances of the insurance company.
After comparing all this, let's conclude the video.  First of all, let us
talk about the
coverage of both the plans.  So there
is no shortage of coverage in both the plans.   It is
not that you will find any feature missing.
Every type of feature is available.  The only
difference is that
you get most of the features inbuilt in HDFC Ago.  You will see more add-on options to make the ICICI
LB Elevate plan more customizable and
flexible.
But whatever
coverage you need, whatever type of coverage and
features you need, you will get it in both these plans.  The
second thing I would
like to tell you is about the scope of coverage.
Although, there is quite sufficient coverage in the Optima Secure plan also.
Secure benefits are
also available.  Restoration also works very well
and you will get plus benefits also.
However, if
you absolutely need multiple times
cumulative bonus like the latest plans, then
you will get it in the ICICI LBAD Elevate plan
which has this Power Booster add-on.  By
taking this, you
can increase this sum insured for unlimited times.
Apart from this, you also get the option of unlimited sum insured
within the ICICI LBD Elevate plan.
Restoration is also unlimited times
by default.  No need to take add ons.
Apart from this, if you take the add-on of Infinite Care, then
you can stretch a single claim to an unlimited amount in a lifetime.
So, somewhere I see
more scope and more options
of coverage in ICICI LBA Elevate plan than Optima Secure.
Now friends let's talk about
pricing.  So, at the initial stage, the
example we took of the cities of Zone A,
here I found the pricing almost the same.  The
slight difference can be
₹1000 to ₹2000 depending on the coverage.  But there
is no big difference.  Because within the ICC LBD
Elevate plan, you have to add a lot of
features as an add-on.
To equate the Secure Benefit, one has to
take the Claim Protector add-on instead of the Protect Benefit.  So
as you keep adding add-ons, the
money for the Elevate plan will also increase accordingly.
But I definitely think it's
because the edge is bended premium.
This gap may increase slightly in the coming years.
You may see higher premiums increasing within HDFC Ergo.
And finally friends, it is the turn of
claims performance that
which of the two
companies is better in terms of claims.  So the claims data
tells us that HDFCR Go is better than ICICI LBRD
Elevate in terms of claim settlement also
and in terms of claims paid ratio also.
However, the solvency and other
stability measures of both the companies are
good.  But in terms of number of claims
settled and money paid against claims,
HDFC Ergo is
performing better than ICICI LBRD General
Insurance.  I hope friends, today
's comparison video would have cleared most of your
doubts about these two plans
and now you will be able to think
about both the plans of these two companies in a
better way with more clarity
and will also be able to take a decision and this was the
purpose of this video.  If you
liked and understood the information given in the video, then to
show your love and support, you
can like the video and
also subscribe to the channel.  If you want
us to bring you such a deep comparison
video of any other plans, then you
can give the name of your favorite plan in the comment section.  I will soon make videos on them too.
I am Harvinder Singh, I will meet
you in the next video.  Till then take
care, stay fit and stay healthy.  Jai Hind.